I said welcome back and today in Kafka
stream we are going to cover this
processors. So before I proceed further
I just want to make sure that we are all
on the same page that we have a good
understanding of Kafka stream
architecture
because if that is not clear you would
find Kafka stream too much difficult.
Okay. So I assume that you have already
seen the architecture video and we are
in line that all we have to is
write topology.
Okay. So all we have to write is
topology and topology has this three
main parts source processor and sync. So
consider this as a part of topology.
So I have already covered the source
where we have discussed about K stream
and K table. Okay. So how to read? So
starting point how to read record from
the Kafka topic. Now let's discuss about
processors.
So processor is of two type stateless
and stateful. Okay. And again if you
have already seen the architecture this
thing might have already been cleared.
Okay. But still let's proceed one level
more deeper.
So first let's see stateless and in the
second part we'll go with the stateful.
So a stateless node
process each record independently.
Okay. So now let's say that in your
Kafka topic
you have record one, record two, record
three, record four.
Then you have written a topology
Kafka stream topology in which you have
written source let's say then processors
and sync each record you can say that it
goes through this pipeline
and
they are processed independently mean
when let's say record two is getting
processed this topology has no
information about previous records like
one I have no information. Okay. So it
does not remember anything from previous
records.
So these are some of the very important
stateless operation filter map value
select key split branch merge. So let's
see quickly but
let's understand one thing which I'm
going to tell you which will help you to
u view this topology
in a better way. Okay. So here if you
see you have a source or you can say
that you have a topic
from topic you read okay you have a
let's say one node everything in a
topology
in a topology
everything is let's say node
now some nodes are like a source node
which read from the topic some nodes are
processing nodes
like stateful, stateless. Some nodes are
like sync. So consider everything as
node. Okay. So this is your
source node and you know that this
output generally K stream or K table. We
have already seen that part. Now after
that now whatever the operation let's
say we do a filter. Now so filter is
also your node. let's say okay certain
processing node so this filter let's say
returns K stream also so now here if you
see generally engineer get confused that
okay from this is the topic Kafka topic
from where I am trying to read I get an
output Kafka stream let's say now on top
of it I did a filter let's say greater
than thousand I again got a Kafka stream
so what is this is it like a different
object is it hold the records.
So the easy way to understand is let's
say this diagram. So from a source okay
then you got a K stream.
So you read the record from the so this
is the let's say topic Kafka topic
okay and the source has read the record
from the topic Kafka topic and output is
k stream now from this k stream let's
say I have built multiple filters filter
greater than equals to th00and it's
output is let's say again a kstream
object which I'm saying high order and
filter less 10,000 it return kream
object let's say I give it a name low
order
now how do you read this kind of a
diagram consider that topology
as a tree okay so you start from where
multiple branches you can go okay this
point then this point from this branch
you can go to this side this side okay
so considered
these K streams K stream or if it return
K table consider those this point
okay now suppose you have to add another
branch from which point
you have to add okay let's say I want to
create a new branch or new filter from
this branch
so let's say this branch or this point
is this Kstream object reference. So
from here I can add another filter let's
say. So that will return another Kstream
object. Okay. So I added one more branch
that's again I got a Kstream object. So
consider this Kstream as a reference to
a point in your topology.
Okay. So that at any particular point
you go and add your another processing
node.
Got it? And completely together it is
like a pipeline. So when any record
comes it goes through your
complete pipeline. So it's uh your K
stream doesn't hold object.
That's the easiest way to understand.
The K stream doesn't hold object. So if
you see multiple K stream does not mean
that your same object is hold by
multiple objects. No
just assume K stream as like in a
particular topology.
Consider this k stream as a different
points so that if in future you have to
add more fil or more processing nodes
just take a reference of a particular k
stream particular point and you can add
your logic there okay
things will get more clear I tried to
explain at this point of but still if
you have any doubt don't worry as we
proceed further things will get more
clear what I'm trying to Okay. So think
Kstream as Kstream represent a stage in
the processing pipeline. It does not
contain data. Multiple Kstream object
allows to continue building the topology
from different stage at the same
pipeline. So this is the same pipeline.
Okay. And these are different stages
points you call it points stages. Okay.
Or K stream object reference. So you can
add your logic another processing node
at any stage. Let's say at this or at
this. Okay.
So if this is clear, let's go with the
first stateless operation which is
filter.
So
I want you to do a hands-on. I will
explain it here. Very very simple. Okay.
In the previous one where we have done
the source, we have already seen in the
architecture also we have already set up
complete setup. We have done we have
read the read the data from the Kafka
topic. We have also seen the sync we are
uh seen that records are going or
published into the Kafka topic also end
to end we have seen. So now I will tell
you different processing nodes we can
have and how to read this method so that
you don't get confused.
The first is filter. Filter keeps only
the record that satisfy a condition. If
the condition return true, the records
continue in the stream. If the condition
return false, the record is dropped.
What does it mean? So stream now you
know you have multiple stages. Okay.
Now let's say the record comes in
and this is let's say my filter
greater than 1,000 and somewhere this
record which is coming it has amount
let's say 200 only. So if this filter
returns true then only it will proceed
further into the stream whether here
here or both otherwise this will get
dropped here itself. It don't proceed
further into the pipeline itself. That's
what this definition says.
Now here if you see the filter method so
now here if you go now let's say we have
already read it. So this one we have
already seen. Okay. So builder dot
stream. So we are trying to read the
record from this Kafka topic. The output
here over here is K stream. Okay. Now
let's say we want a filter.
So orders.
So what I'm doing from where from which
stage I have to add this filter
currently at this we have
Kstream
orders.
Okay. Now where I have to add a filter
on top of this, right? So consider this
as a stage. So I am using here building
it here orders dot filter.
Okay. So if you go inside this
just read this. Okay. So here if you see
filter
predicate go inside this predicate.
If you have if you have a Java
background pretty much sure because in
Java I have already covered this
functional interface and this generics
clearly. So there should not be any
doubt. So now here if you see that when
we invoke a filter method okay so this
predicate is a functional interface. So
we have to provide an implementation for
this. So what does it implementation
takes? Two parameter K which is a key V
which is a value. Okay. Then you will we
will write our own logic and output is
boolean true or false. Okay. After this
predicate
the output is the same K stream KV key
and value. Okay.
So the same thing the predicate is over
this. So we have to provide an
implementation for this one. That's what
I have done here. So here if you see
order I am using from this stage I am
building I am adding another filter
processing node. So dot filter. Now dot
filter parameter is predicate and this
predicate is a functional interface
which has this method. We have to
provide an implementation of this. So
two parameter I take key and value.
Key and value. Okay. So this is just any
parameter name you can give key and
value
and you can provide an implementation
for it whatever the filter you want to
add. So order right. So order dot get
total amount greater than 1,000. Okay.
So I have written my logic this should
be greater than 1,000. So this should
return true. Okay. So I have written my
logic here. And ultimately this filter
if it return true
then it will add it. It will further
send this k stream. The same part the K
stream string
order the same. Okay. Whatever we have
it return the same thing. Whatever the
key value original from where we are
building right whatever the
K stream key and value is there the same
thing it returns also.
Got it? So our processing node is filter
amount greater than 1,000. So this is
our processing nodes.
But this K stream
now act as a reference to the filter
processing node. So currently our it was
orders.
Okay. So here it was
pointing to source read from the topic.
Now in the pipeline I have added a
filter from this order itself.
Okay. And this is also a K stream. This
is also a K stream. Now in future if you
add another filter. So now you have two
K stream here this and this. Now let's
say if you have to add it from here so
use this K stream. Okay. So it would be
like here another filter. But if you
have to use this K stream it would be
like beneath this. So you got now the
purpose of K stream. K stream do not
hold data. It is just an stage in the
pipeline. Okay. So that we can continue
build the topology.
So filter is clear. The second is map.
Map transform the record into another
record. So let's say we have a key, we
have a value. So using map we can either
change key, we can either change value
or we can either change both.
Okay.
So how to use a map? So this is the map
method. Okay. So now if you see map what
is the parameter it takes
if you see the parameter it look little
complex but slowly if you analyze one by
one open the key value mapper so let's
see that also
map
just open anything okay so what does
this map take key value mapper so now
open key value mapper so again it's a
functional interface So we have to
provide an implementation for this
method. The parameter is key. Okay.
And uh another parameter is value v key
k and v. Okay. So the first two
parameter
this k v.
So this is your k key. This is your v
value. Now after whatever we process the
output we return is this third parameter
which this take. What is this third
parameter? V R. So here if you see the
third is this key value.
So uh this is key
this is value
and now here if you see
key value. So this is the key value pair
complete.
Okay. So this is the output. What is the
key? What is the value? So we are
returning the key value pair. Okay. So
here if you see how I am using it
orders do map. Okay. So in map
we have a key value mapper. Now key
value mapper we have to provide an
implementation for this. So it has two
parameter key and value. So two
parameter key comma order key and value
that's we are building on orders right
so order has this key and this is value
okay now we what whatever the logic you
have to do change the key change compute
the value whatever you have to do what
is the output the output of this
implementation is VR this VR is nothing
but a third parameter on this key value
mapper this is one this is two and this
is three so we have to return a key
value. So we have to return a new key
new value.
So key value pair dot pair this is our
new key order key.
Okay. And the value I am returning order
only. So no change in value whatever the
earlier it has an order I am whatever
the order I have previously I'm still
returning but I change the key. I just
added order hyphen. So you can change
only key you can change only value. You
can change both.
All you have to is understand this how
to use this methods. Okay.
So got it. And now the output of this
ultimately is Kstream KR, VR your new
key new value. Okay. So my new key new
value. Currently new key is still a
string. So it's still a string and the
new values are still an order or still
order. But it can be changed also.
Got it? So currently if the input record
was this now after this map the input
record would be order hyphen whatever
the key 101 and this order
got it.
So like map is used to change either key
or value or both. Similarly, we have
only map values. Only value can be
changed. No key change is allowed. Okay.
So, that is also possible. So, here I
think you can now read it. Like if I
open map values,
let's open it. Map
values.
Let's open it. Now, here if you see what
what how you would be a how would you
read this? So map values parameter it
take is value mapper go inside this
value mapper. So we have to provide an
implementation for this and it take your
only v. Okay. So only value it takes and
what the output you get the new value
the old value it takes and returns the
new value. Okay. And ultimately
your output is K stream old key new
value
that's the same thing order map values
the old value your old value order. Now
how you want to compute a new value
totally up to you. You creating a
totally new object but only thing is we
have to return the new value. It could
be of anything. Okay. And whatever you
will send output is K stream the old key
but the new value which you are
returning.
Okay. Similarly we have select key only
key change is allowed. No value is no
value is changed. Okay. So if you have
only keys change then use this select
key.
So orders dot select key. Now if you
open select key
can you read this? Now go inside key
value mapper. So key comm, v. So two
parameter it takes the output it take is
vr. The third one what is this third
parameter it takes? So we have a key,
we have a value and here if you see KR
whatever the third output we will return
that would be added as a KR and KR is
used in your key ultimately.
Okay. So two parameter take your old key
old value. Now whatever you have to do
find out the new key. Okay. whatever the
new key is. So, K stream is your new key
old value.
Okay. So, now see this the method map.
Can we change the key? Yes. Can we
change the value? Yes. And if you
remember from the architecture video,
if the key is changed,
okay, then repartition
can be initiated.
Can you recall what repartition is?
It create a totally new repartition
topic so that all the keys
all the records with the new key goes to
the same topic. If you have any doubt
with this repartition, I would highly
encourage kindly check out the rearchite
uh architecture video. In that kindly
check the repartition part, okay, it
will get clear. But remember that at
this point of time repartition do not
happen but you can say that it is
eligible for repartition.
I will tell you exactly when the
repartition will happen. But at this
point of time when a key is changed when
a key is changed then it is eligible for
repartition. Okay. Map values keys
change no value change yes. Is it
eligible for repartition? No. Because
key is not changed. Similarly select
key. Key issue change no. Eligible for
repartition later yes. So whenever a key
is changed repartition can happen in
future and I will tell you how.
So the same thing when key is changed it
does not initiate the repartition
immediately. Repartition initiated when
downstream operation require record to
be partitioned by the new key whenever
it is required. Generally by this two
operation it happen group by key or
join.
Okay. So check this video Kafka stream
architecture there I have told you about
this subtopology where it create a
repartition topic and everything I have
already explained in depth like whatever
the uh knowledge I have regarding this
repartition. Okay with this things will
get clear to you.
The another is a split branch.
Now here if you see the problem with the
below code whatever we have seen filter
right now let's say order currently at
this point of let's say this is stage in
the pipeline is this is orders K stream
now from this
from this order
I have written orders dot filter one I
have created one filter
filter greater than 1,000
So this is another case stream.
Okay. So I have written another case
stream low value order dot filter less
than equals to,000. So from this order
itself order I have another filter less
than equals to,000. This is also case
stream low value orders. This is high
value orders.
Now
let's say
a order comes in okay a record comes in
currently what would happen so this will
it will check both both the filter okay
hey can I go here filter greater than
th000 let's say it is u
200 so it will go here hey can I go to
this path
greater than thousand. No. Okay. But at
parallel it can also go to this pipeline
also. Hey can I go to this less than
equals to the n? Yes. So it will proceed
further down this line.
But the important point which I wanted
to mention that both the conditions are
validated. So if you have certain
condition
that both get true then your record flow
into both.
Okay, the same record goes into both.
For example, just take filter
person equals to employee
filter person equals to
wise principal.
So now when the record comes in it will
check hey person is employee yes. Now it
will also check because both the
condition will check. Person is vice
principal. Yes, he's an a person is an
employee also and it's a vice principal.
So this condition is also true. So it
will go here also. So got it. My point
here is that when we have two filters
okay for each record both the filters
will get executed. So above approach is
okay when a record can move in both the
direction. else. Why for every record we
need both filters to be checked? If you
have a scenario like this or this
then this is something like extra work
we are doing for every record both the
filters we are executing it. That's
where split branch comes in. It's like
if
else if
else if and else branch like we have a
chaining right? If else if else if else
if and else last else the same thing. So
here if you see you can simply do this
orders dotsplit
you can now have split this is the
orders now split multiple branches. So
this or this or this or so if anything
get true the other conditions will not
even checked.
So dotsplit dot branch. So first branch
I'm checking. So again key value. Now
whatever the condition you have just
check it. Just give this branch as name.
Let's say I give it a name premium.
Great. Amount is total greater than
2,000. I give this branch a name
premium. Now another dot branch key
value. Your logic. Let's say greater
than,000. I give this branch a name
high.
Otherwise the default branch is low. So
I I have just created three branch. One
is premium, one is high, another is low.
Okay. Now
we can get a stage for this all three.
So Kstream premium order branches dot
get use the name premium you will get a
K stream. Branches.get high you will get
a Kstream. Branches.get low you will get
a Kstream. Now these are like a
reference point. So if from further
branch let's say from high branch you
have to build something you can use this
high orders dot something.
Got it? But this is like or condition.
If this condition get true premium one
high and low will not get executed.
So it's like an if else if else change
not all condition will get executed.
Similarly we have merge. Merge is just
the opposite of split. split one stream
becomes many merges like many stream
become one. So see this is the example
the same example I have taken the the
orders I have split into multiple
branches okay one premium one high
another low three branches I have done
so now if you want I can merge let's say
these two
I I can merge all this like premium
orders
branch
dot merge with high order dot merge low
order like if you more dot merge dot
merge you can add more branches
together. Okay. And then output would be
one now.
Okay. But one condition is that whatever
the
stream you are merging they should have
a same type of key and same type of
value. Then only you can merge. Key and
order type should be same for all.
Okay.
Do practice with your hands. Okay. And
if you have any doubt let me know. But
these are the frequently used stateless
operation. There could be more but these
are heavily used. Now in the next part I
will show you stateful operation. Okay.
And uh after that the remaining part
would be like say stateless
is done.
After stateful the only thing would be
left is window and with that our k
stream would be full done. Only these
two left.
Okay, any doubt let me know in the
comment section. We'll discuss further.
Bye.